hello this is Frank defreitis and
welcome to another week of Holo talk for
the week of March 19th 2
000 I'm joined in the studio right now
with Michelle Roy who's sort of becoming
a sidekick with the whole talk show oh
thank you the trustee sidekick like
Batman and Robin Batman and Robin yeah
Frank and Michelle okay
um we have a number of special
broadcasts that's coming up for you over
the next few weeks we visited the center
for holographic Arts in New York City
actually Queens right that's what and
they had their opening there with a
number of their Artisan Residency
program students works that were on
display and we had an opportunity to
interview a number of the people who
were
presented in that show so over the next
few weeks we're going to be bringing you
these programs and Michelle joined me in
New York City to interview them as well
and Michelle
I have no idea what I want to ask you
well that should work well basically why
don't you tell the listeners we know
you've been on the whole talk show
before in your special on careers
um once again why don't you take a
minute to tell the listeners what it is
that we'll be doing together when we do
programs together
what what do you mean well ask me that
question differently say for instance
someone comes to see us do a program oh
okay what would it be
what would be that's mine that's my
interest in all of this is uh related to
um
careers and lasers and holography and
photonics is in terms of how they can
turn into careers for people so for
example when we went to uh Queens
yesterday uh you were talking to people
about more of the you know technical
aspect of what they were doing in the
artistic pieces of it although I like to
talk about the artistic Parts too uh but
you did a very nice job oh thank you yes
thank you but my uh major interest is in
what makes someone want to do this what
makes someone want to go into a
holography what kinds of mental disorder
exactly trying to identify I am trying
to hook people up with some psychiatric
you know resources if necessary no just
you know finding out what what interests
people about the field what do they
enjoy about the field what kinds of
opportunities are out there some of the
people that we spoke with yesterday
talked about like internship
possibilities and artists in Residence
programs and so forth classes that you
can take that you know let people who
are interested in pursuing it a little
more deeply have an opportunity to get
some different kinds of experiences and
if they want to turn it into a career
then you know there would be a way to do
that so that was more my take on what
what we were doing and why we were there
which when we do programs together
that's where I fill in as well as
looking at how people can turn which is
obviously a passion I mean that came
through loud and clear in all of the
interviews that we did yesterday that
people do this because they really love
it um and I'm a big believer in taking
the things that you really love to do
figuring out how to make some money off
of it so you know that's basically uh
sort of the approach I was taking do you
think people basically mention their
passion because they don't make a lot of
money I'm sure that's part of it I mean
particularly I mean we were talking to
artists so you know people who are are
not using lasers in like an industrial
setting or something like that where it
might be a little bit different and you
have business driving it so that there
is money
um yeah I would say that those people
probably you know they have to be driven
by something because it certainly wasn't
money that it is you know the love of
the field the way that I use holography
and a lot of the workshops that I do is
not so much to allow people to move on
and become holographers as it is to turn
them on to what lasers they do as far as
communication Technologies and things of
that nature where they could go out and
get a very high paying job because quite
a demand for people who are skilled
right in that field well see the thing
that I thought was interesting about
yesterday was I I am more in many ways
more aware of you know lasers in terms
of using it in Communications and that
sort of thing more of that business kind
of field and the thing that was fun
about yesterday was talking to people
who are artists you know when you use
you know who who really see the Hologram
as the thing yeah um so that was just
sort of a different you know perspective
yeah and holography is a great way to
get people to come in and experience
life sure right I mean you could bring
someone into a classroom or someone into
a workshop and just teach them about
lasers but holography is a wonderful way
to combine a lot of different elements
of learning and at the same time allow
them to get experience with lasers and
so much more constructive than shining
laser pens yes
we have a program coming up where you
can come and see Michelle and I at the
Smithsonian on May 6th and we're going
to have an exhibit of holograms there
will be doing presentations throughout
the day at the Hershel at the hershon
Museum of the Smithsonian which is right
on the mall and we'll have more
information on that as time goes on but
over the next few weeks you're going to
be hearing some programs that Michelle
and I put together while we were in New
York and that will sort of lead us up to
the program
zoning in Washington coming up on May 6
and that's the program for uh for the
public we also have another program
coming up for a national Teachers
Conference that will be there as well so
let's move on to the interview our first
guest on the show in this series is one
of the co-directors of the center for
holographic Arts Anna Maria Nicholson
and we also have a link to the Center
for holographic Arts webpage that you
can click on that and visit their
website as well so let's move on to the
interview Michelle thank you very much
for coming into the studio and going on
the trip and those of you out there in
Hollow talk land will be hearing more
from Michelle and you'll hear me shut up
a little bit more and let her talk a
little bit more which many of you may be
grateful
so let's move on to the interview and
we'll see you next week a new show each
week don't forget to tune in see ya see
ya
[Music]
hi this is Frankie Freitas I'm here in
Long Island City better known as Queens
right
and we have the opening of the hollow
Center's exhibit is this the uh in fact
I have Anna Maria Nicholson with me now
how are you fine thank you it's the
center for the Hall of
center for the holographic Arts okay
version for the internet the website is
hollowcenter.com right exactly and we'll
have a link to that on the web page so
people can go visit that site while
they're listening to the show okay great
why don't you take a moment to tell us a
little bit about some of the pieces that
are on exhibit here and we'll get back
and also ask you about the programs that
you have here as well well we're
extremely pleased with this our very
first exhibit
for the artists who received the artist
and residency program and this is the
first year and it's amazing to us how
good the work is and what to me
especially well all of the work but Mary
Harmon's work
is a really breakthrough for holography
I think the fact that the Holograms come
off the wall and become part of an
installation and part of it and they are
extremely beautiful she did them all
here and that beautiful work could not
have been created without the center
that's why I feel that we're doing a
very good job as far as providing this
opportunity for artists to come and work
how long has the center been here this
is our second year and we are funded for
one more year
that we hope to continue to be funded
further but we don't know yet now you do
Post portraits here as well right yes
yes we do pause portraits and also
um jobs uh on commission for um trade
shows and things like that that helps us
with with the money situation here so
I'm assuming that anyone can come in or
contact the studio here and say I'd like
to have a portrait done of myself or my
family or anything like that right
absolutely I've been doing portrait as
you know before I got known for many
years
and he has been you know has sustained
me as far as a financial situation in
holography now the center is continuing
with that and I do the portraits Within
will be both collaborating and you can
make an appointment it's very reasonable
a thousand dollars for the portrait and
um that's all it takes what size spinal
reflection hologram is that when it's
finished it's about it's 11 12 by 14.
yeah it's a 30 by 40 centimeter that is
correct yeah
um is this the first exhibit that you
have had here for your Artisan Residency
program yes this is the very first and
we plan to have one every year for the
artist of that year of the of the past
year now I know you have a program here
have you reviewed any applications for
your next airs here not yet uh because
when when we have the uh the deadline is
July 15th so no we have received hardly
any applications yet although we are
very open to everyone as far as the
gallery goes if someone happens to be in
the New York City area can they come
over here to Queens and just come in and
see the exhibit they can't if they
telephones ahead of time and also this
exhibition is only going to be here for
two weeks then it's going to travel down
to a gallery in Fort Myers in Florida
and from there it's going to go to the
Tucson Museum of Contemporary Art
so that we're very pleased that he's
doing the round okay I'm going to turn
the microphone over to Michelle Roy
who's here with us today hi Michelle how
you doing good Frank how are you we're
doing more and more work together in
holography and lasers that's right so uh
here's the microphone and here's
Michelle Roy
um I am interested in in my uh
background and is in um helping people
decide on careers and what they want to
do with their life so what interests me
about all of this is how do you decide
to go into holography what made you
decide to uh to do this well for me
personally as with so many other first
wave or second wellographers we saw a
hologram and we fell in love with it and
said this is the purpose of Our Lives
you know
some do our great regret later but you
know
very very cool medium It's a Wonderful
medium the expensive medium at the
moment we are very fortunate to have two
assistants who just walked off the
street practically who are now helping
us and extremely interested in
continuing holography as their artistic
medium so do you consider yourself an
artist or a technician or both no I'm an
artist and I have had uh shows in in art
galleries and so on
um
so what made you decide to work in this
medium is this the only medium that you
work in and it okay what attracted you
to to this as opposed to you know being
a painter or a sculptor or I
did a wonderful medium it's a magical
the
reality being there and not being there
a space that is illusory
um that's the whole thing is it's a
dream
basically that we can explore and create
it and now extremely excited because I'm
about to start a whole new series with a
model that I have who's now coming from
Paris and to have a
figure coming through Veil coming
through small coming through to our from
one reality to another
it was speaking earlier to your intern
who's here and um yes
um can you tell me about your internship
program and how that works uh how uh you
know someone who might be interested in
getting involved in holography might be
able to you know participate through the
internship we'll be extremely open to
makiko Founders on the internet
she probably told you she came from
Japan to study holography uh we we've
done in our budget we don't can't pay so
but what we what we do is we teach them
holography we the equipment is there for
them and we help them and encourage them
in future and also in not only
holography but art you know Dan and I
are all handed this so right
what kinds of um things is is she is
makika learning how to do what are can
you give me an idea of sort of the lack
of a better word the curriculum although
that sounds a little too you know
structured maybe it is too structured
she's here she helps us for whatever we
need to do because we'll do quite a lot
of shooting
um she's now totally expert as far as
the dark room is concerned he's helping
us set up uh in the CW table and she's
helping us with the pulse shooting what
I want to do when we have a week or two
free is have her create her own hologram
now I think it's time and then with I
will walk her through the process so if
someone were interested in obtaining an
internship they would just need to to
contact you okay stop and and you'll
interview them and do a little bit of
checkup and uh if they are in particle
with us uh and vice versa then we have
two now one is David baraski and this is
this hologram here is one of his and
we're very pleased and amazed this is
his third hologram in his life very
educated he's a student at NYU and he
just again fell in love with holography
and he I think he's thinking of
Photography as he's medium nature medium
what I'm just saying okay oh okay then
well you made me lose my train of
thought now okay
yeah
he's sorry that I'm making him now have
to go in and cut this all out
this is what the listeners like this
stuff oh all right the banter back and
forth
um so if someone were thinking about
holography what would you encourage them
to do if a kid is in you know high
school or in college what are the kinds
of things that they would need to to do
to
go on the way
um
where all the information is and check
out the other websites um I don't know
of any other well Dan gives by the
lessons uh he could they could do that
they could contact us
and I don't know I think that the School
of Visual Arts has a course in
holography I don't know of anything else
so there are some some programs that are
out there where the kids could take
courses or students could take some
courses
um but this may be the only place where
they could completely focus on
holography
don't forget that the great advantage
that we have is that we have a pulse
laser and with a pulse laser which is
you I think there is one in San
Francisco there may be another one
somewhere in the country but we're very
few and with that opens up a whole new
other themes for for the Young Artists
uh and all the ease of making a hologram
in in the fact that you can use human
beings you know so I think that's our
very very unique and by the way people
we we do rent the pulse per day a very
reasonable 750 a day and with all our
help right yeah so somebody wanted to in
and try it out and and see you know how
to create their own hologram that they
could come in here and do that
it then they want to transfer it they'll
we can also help them with that great
great I appreciate it thank you very
much
I
okay I think what we'll do is get
someone else in and then we'll just
continue with the show